《越狱》前情提要K
Previously on Prison Break:
我要越狱 你要帮助我哥和我一起逃出去
I'm breaking out. And you're gonna make sure my brother goes with me.
对不起，亨利
I'm sorry, Henry.
这段留言是给犸丽的 我会在伊斯塔帕机场等你
This message is for Maricruz. I'll be there in the airport in lxtapa waiting for you.
苏克，之后如果你遇到麻烦 在留言板上留言
Sucre, down the road, if you're in trouble, post a note on the message board.
-网站叫什么？ -欧洲金翅网站
- What's it called? - Europeangoldfinch. Net.
那是一种鸟对吧？
That's a bird, right?
收拾行李，我们搬家
Go pack your things. We're moving.
我们是一家人 同归于尽也无妨
We will be a family if it kills us.
把事办好，你就能回家了
Pull this off and you're halfway home,
你还记得家的模样吧？
You remember what home is like, don't you?
离我的家人远一点
Stay away from my family.
她需要吃药 两天没吃药会发作
She needs that medicine. She can't go two days without it.
-我不舒服 -甜心啊
- I don't feel good. - Oh, sweetie.
迈克，我要这一切结束
I want for this to be over.
我也是，现在都要靠 你父亲给你的东西
That makes two of us. A question of looking at whatever your father gave you.
只是一把钥匙
It's just a key.
东西就锁在 雪茄俱乐部的箱子里
It's locked in a box inside that cigar club.
我不是通缉要犯 把钥匙给我，我去开
I'm not a wanted fugitive. Give me the key. I'll do it.
你想去走走吗？
Wanna take a walk?
丹奎迪小姐
Ms. Tancredi.
我有事要和你谈谈
I need to have a word with you.
-丹奎迪小姐 -好的
- Ms. Tancredi. - Of course.
丹奎迪小姐？小姐？
Ms. Tancredi? Ma'am?
-丹奎迪小姐？ -我们该走了
- Ms. Tancredi? - It's time to go.
小姐？
Ma'am?
他们从后面出去了
They're going out back.
快走
Come on.
（明尼苏达州，明尼亚波利）
（明尼苏达州 明尼亚波利/圣保罗国际机场）
请接小儿科
Pediatrics, please.
（科罗拉多州，杜兰戈）
- Hello? - Cameron,
-喂？ -卡麦隆
-爸 -你好吗，小家伙？
- Hi, Dad. - How you doing, big guy?
-很好，我在吃午餐 -好吃吗？
- Good, I'm eating my lunch, - oh, how is it?
很恶心
Pretty disgusting.
也许你妈可以做晚餐 送过去给你吃
Maybe your mom can bring you some dinner from home.
-你今天看过医生了吗？ -看了
- Did you see the doctor today? - Yeah,
他说我这礼拜就能回家 只要我不上街去
He said I could go home this week, as long as I stay out of the street,
你是个聪明的孩子 你知道怎么过马路
You're a smart young man. You know how to cross the street.
你在生我的气吗？
Are you mad at me?
听我说
Listen to me.
没有人在生你的气 这也不是你的错
No one is mad at you, and this wasn't your fault.
该保护你的人是我
I should've been looking out for you.
可是你又不在场
You weren't even there.
我应该在你身旁才对
But I should've been.
真是的K伙伴，我得走了 我晚点再打给你好吗？
Oh, man. Hey, buddy, listen, I gotta go. But I'll call you back later, okay?
-好，再见 -卡麦隆
- Okay. Bye. - Cameron,
我爱你
I love you.
小卡？
Cam?
富兰克林有何消息？
Yeah? What have we got on Franklin?
今早之后就没有新线索
Nothing new since this morning.
明尼苏达州的餐厅抢案 有另一个目击者确定见过他
Another witness from the Minnesota diner robbery gave a positive ID.
很好，我十五分钟前 刚抵达明尼亚波利
Good, because I just landed in Minneapolis 15 minutes ago.
-还有其他线索吗？ -有，他女儿蒂蒂
- Anything else? - Yeah, the girl, Dede,
她显然有病在身 某种慢性疾病
Apparently, she's been ill. Some chronic condition.
把富兰克林的照片传真到 明尼斯达州东南部每家医院
Fax Franklin's mug shot to every hospital in southeastern Minnesota.
已经办了，好运的话 她病入膏肓，他就会现身
Already done. With any luck, she'll get sick enough to need one and he'll show his face.
-你没有小孩对吧，兰恩？ -没有
- You don't have kids, do you, Lang? - Nope.
有新发展再通知我
Call me when you have something else.
我要买这个
I'll take that.
-我们没拿到 -什么？
- We didn't get it. - What?
我们得马上再回去
And we need to get back in there soon.
一旦“公司” 发现莎拉去过那里
Once the Company finds out sara was in there...
他们马上会开始起疑
...it won't belong before they start wondering why.
你们到俱乐部附近找地方等待 我们要把车开走
Find a spot close to the club and sit tight. We're gonna take the car.
-几小时后回来 -你们要去哪里？
- Be back in a couple of hours. - Where you going?
我发现俱乐部里 有个会员可以帮助我们
Turns out that maybe there's one member of that club who can help us.
谁？
Who?
（亨利波普）
Pope?
波普？
等一下
Just a minute.
亨利
Henry.
你来这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
除了弃保潜逃 和逃避司法之外？
Aside from jumping bail and evading the authorities?
有件事你必须知道 但我要先知道你是否愿意听
There's something that you need to hear. But first, I need to know if you'll listen.
莎拉，我们没有什么好谈的
Sara, we've got nothing to discuss.
拜托，只要五分钟 你听完了要我们走，我们就走
Please, I need five minutes. After that, if you want us to, we'll leave.
我们是指谁？
Who's us?
片名：越狱风云
剧名：罪恶血统
-我不想惹麻烦 -很好，因为我们不是来找麻烦的
- I don't want any trouble. - Good. Because that's not why we're here.
你的脑袋有问题吗？ 大摇大摆走进来？你可是通缉犯
What the hell are you thinking about, waltzing in here? You're a wanted criminal.
我看你忘了 我整个事业生涯K
In case you've forgotten, I dedicated my career...
我的一生都致力于 将你们这种人关在牢里
...my entire life, to keeping people like you behind bars.
你说的是有罪的人 我哥是清白的
You're talking about guilty people. My brother is innocent.
-我们也许有证据可证明 -我不在乎，你们出去
- We have the evidence to prove it. - I don't care. I want you out.
东西就在金皇冠俱乐部的箱子里 而你是会员
It's in a locked box at the Corona de oro Club and you're a member.
-出去 -亨利，请你听他说
- Out. - Henry, please listen.
莎拉，我很想说 你早该学到教训了
Sara, I'm tempted to say you should've known better.
但你的所作所为K
But after what you did...
我父亲在调查 柏劳的案子时遭到谋杀
My father was looking into the Burrows case when he was murdered.
我在他的尸体上 只能找到这把钥匙
This key is the only thing I could recover from his body.
（阿拉巴马州，科内库郡）
我们要去哪里？
Where are we going?
孩子们饿了 我们已经开了一整天的车
They're hungry. We've been driving all day.
吃糖果
Chick-o-stick.
他们需要真正的食物
They need real food.
马上就到，小宝贝
Soon enough, pumpkin.
老天爷
Alackaday.
真是荒谬、丑陋
Miscreants. Defilers.
肮脏
Defacers.
邪恶
Despoilers.
这是哪里？
What is this?
我的老家
My home.
（墨西哥泰帕坦 伊斯塔帕外三十五里处）
不会吧，不会吧，不会吧
Oh, no, no, no.
别闹了
Oh, really, no.
你要去哪里？
-机场 -算你幸运
-还有多远？ -二十分钟就到
你赶搭飞机吗？
我女友的飞机四点会降落
应该赶得上
太好了
-我是卡德纳 -你在多远的地方？
二十里外
收到
怎么回事？
我是机场警卫
有美国逃犯 搭机入境之类的事
（医学中心）
（明尼苏达州，明尼亚波利）
好，甜心 你坐在这里好吗？
Okay. All right, sweetie, why don't you sit over here, okay?
好，我过去跟 那位女士说话好吗？
All right. I'm gonna go over there and I'm gonna talk to the lady, all right?
你需要什么吗？你确定？
So you need anything? You sure?
好
Okay.
-有事吗？ -我女儿蒂蒂，她病得不轻
- Yes? - My daughter, Dede, she's really sick.
她从小时候开始 肾脏就有问题
She's had this kidney thing since she was real young.
-大多在左K -她在哪里？
- It's on the left... - Where is she?
她坐在那里
She's sitting right there.
-你们来过吗？ -没有，我们是外地人
- Have you been here before? - No. We're from out of town.
保险卡借我看一下好吗？
Can I see your insurance card?
不K我没有保险
No. No, I don't have any insurance.
我退伍之后 军方就不支付我的保险
After I left the Army, they discontinued my insurance.
你是亨尼奔郡的居民吗？
Are you a resident of Hennepin County?
我说过，我们是外地人
Like I said, we're from out of town.
你有驾照吗？
Do you have a driver's license?
听着，我没有驾照 保险卡那些东西
Look, I don't have a driver's license, an insurance card or anything like that.
但我知道法律规定 你们得看我的女儿
But I do know the law. You have to see my little girl.
-我去找我上司 -很好
- I'm gonna go get my supervisor. - Good.
我根本不在乎你 或是你哥的死活
I don't give a rat's ass about you or your brother.
我信任你，我照顾你 我把你当儿子看待
I trusted you. I took you under my wing. I treated you like my own son.
我相信你
I believed you.
你日复一日欺骗我 哪种人会作出这种事？
Day after day, you lied to me. What kind of a man does that?
-一个狗急跳墙的人 -对
- A desperate one. - Yeah.
你们今天来这里 算是铸下大错
Well, you two made a big mistake coming here today.
你让我别无选择 我现在就要通知警方
You gave me no choice. I'm gonna notify the authorities right now.
对不起K
I'm sorry...
我不能让你这么做
...but I can't let you do that.
我不想伤害你，亨利
I don't wanna hurt you, Henry.
-拿着枪的人还如此大言不惭 -为了说服你，我只能出此下策
- Said by the man with the gun. - Lf it's the way I can convince you, so be it.
拿枪指着我 是无法说服我的
Well, you're not gonna convince me by doing that.
-我不是你想的那样 -我很清楚你是怎样的人，迈克
- I'm not the man you think I am. - I have a pretty good idea who you are.
如果你真了解，你该知道 我根本不想进福克斯河监狱
If that's true, then you already know I never wanted to be in Fox River.
我根本不想认识你，亨利 我更不想毁了你的人生
I never wanted to meet you, Henry. I certainly didn't wanna ruin your life.
是吗？那你可真行
Yeah? You've done a pretty damn good job.
所有你对他说的话 我自己都说过，亨利
You're not saying anything to him I haven't said myself, Henry.
我查过这件事 他对你说的是实话
I've looked into this. What he's saying to you is true.
我只想救我哥一条命 我要世人知道真相
I just want my brother's life back. I want people to know the truth.
我愿意为这放弃一切 舍弃我的性命
I'd give anything for that. I'd lay down my life.
你拿着枪 此话当然说得轻松
That's easy for you to say, standing on that side of the gun.
如果是你拿着枪呢？
What if I'm standing on this side?
有其他地方 更符合你的需求
There are places that can better serve your needs.
-听着，我清楚我有权利 -这里不是一般医疗机构
- Look, I know my rights, okay? - This isn't a primary care facility.
我们提供的是 有生命危险的必要医疗
We provide necessary care in life-threatening situations.
我知道你想干嘛 你要等到她死掉才帮她吗？
I know. Are you gonna wait until she's dead before you give her help?
-你是这意思吗？ -我不想跟你争辩，先生
- Is that what you're telling me? - I'll not argue with you.
这里是医院 不是游民收容所
This is a hospital, not a homeless shelter.
什么？
A what?
你刚刚说什么？
What did you just say to me?
真不敢相信有你们这种人
I can't believe you people.
走吧，看医生的人太多了
Come on. The line is a little bit too long, okay?
我们去别的地方
We'll go somewhere else.
我们要去哪里？
Where are we going?
去找其他医生，甜心
We gotta find another doctor, sweetie.
天啊
My God.
我们走
Let's go.
让开！
Move!
抱紧，宝贝
Hold on, baby.
富兰克林！
Franklin!
欢迎搭乘明尼亚波利自动火车
Thank you for riding the Minneapolis Auto Train,
-不要挡路！ -下车时请动作快
- Move out of the way! - Please disembark quickly,
该死，站住！
FBI! Stop! Stop!
好K
Okay, okay. Okay, okay.
好，听着
All right. Look.
-宝贝，你得下来 -不要
- Baby, you gotta get down. - No.
-不K甜心，你得下来 -放开他，孩子
- No, no, you gotta get down. - You gotta let him go.
-下来 -放开他，孩子
- Get down. - You gotta let him go.
-快点 -不要
- Come on. - No.
车门马上就要关了
The doors will be closing momentarily,
-她不肯放手 -别让她承担你的错误
- she's not letting go. - Don't let her pay for your mistakes.
你听到了吗？
You hear me?
我可以毫不迟疑地 立刻朝你开枪
I could shoot you right now and not even think twice.
但你不会
But you won't.
你太了解监狱了 不可能鲁莽的毁了自己的人生
You've spent too much time around prisons to throw your life away like that.
-你到底想耍什么把戏？ -很简单
- What the hell are you trying to pull? - It's simple.
那把钥匙可以找回清白人的自由 拜托，亨利
That's the key to an innocent man's freedom. Come on, Henry.
我们都清楚这件事不单纯
We both know there's something going on here.
已有太多人因此丧命 看着我的眼睛
Too many people have died. Look me in the eye.
告诉我你不相信 这件事另有隐情
Tell me you don't believe there's a cover-up going on right now.
我并没有道德义务，迈克
I've got no moral obligations here, Michael.
以我的所知来说 林克罪不可赦
As far as I know, Lincoln is as guilty as hell.
跟我们搭十分钟的车去查真相 我只要求这么多
Then take a 10-minute drive with me and we'll find out. That's all I ask.
亨利，你之前调查过 你也质疑过
Henry, you've looked into this before. You've thought about it.
的确
I have.
最后我下了一个结论
And I've come to one conclusion.
这件事与我无关
This has nothing to do with me.
但我是执法的人
But I am a man of the law...
而现在有个通缉要犯 就站在我家里！
...and right now, I've got a convicted felon standing inside my house.
也许我还有办法 让你改变心意
Well, maybe there's something I can offer you to make you change your mind.
你打算对我们做什么？
What do you intend to do with us?
你这蠢材
Dumb grease monkey.
你根本不配拿最低工资
You don't deserve minimum wage.
才怪，我可是大夜班耶
The hell I don't. Working graveyard?
一个人不配拿到K
There ain't no man who deserves more pennies...
比自己智商还高的时薪
...on the dollar per hour than they got IQ points in his head.
我又不笨
I ain't stupid.
你家的人似乎都一样笨
Seems equal stupid as the rest of you.
笨会遗传的
Seems to run in the genes.
泰迪
Teddy.
十个同义词，选一个字
Ten synonyms. Pick a word.
选一个字
Pick a word.
毁灭
Destroy.
毁灭的十个同义词
Ten synonyms for destroy.
废止
Annul.
毁坏
Mutilate.
消除、废除
Liquidate. Abrogate.
清除、蹂躏、删除
Quell. Ravage. Expunge.
破坏、灭绝、消灭
Demolish. Extirpate. Extinguish.
-你听到了吗？ -笨个头啦
- You see that? - Stupid, my pail.
我的儿子将来要当总统
My boy's gonna be president.
你怎么没在念书？
How come you ain't studying?
因为我累了
Because I'm tired.
因为我觉得自己是 马戏团里的怪胎
Because I feel like a circus freak.
听着K
Well, now...
念书是为你好
...it's in your own best interest.
你不知道吗？
Don't you understand that?
你总有一天会当总统
Now, you gonna be president someday.
牢记我的话
You mark my words.
西奥多
Theodore.
西奥多，你有听见吗？
Theodore, do you hear me?
我们来这里做什么？
What are you gonna do with us?
我们要在这里落地生根
We're gonna put down some roots.
你之前要我的命，保罗
You wanted me dead, Paul.
我只是听命行事
Just following orders.
你用莫须有的罪名 送我上电椅
You sent me to the chair for something I didn't do.
为了你的总统 你什么都做得出来
All for your president. You were willing to do that.
-只是听命行事 -史泰门说你爱她
- Just following orders. - Steadman said you loved her.
史泰门是发了疯的笼中鸟
Steadman was a deranged man that lived in a locked box.
热爱权势胜过生命的人 是不会有人爱的
You don't love someone that loves power more than life.
-讲话真酸 -有吗？
- Bitter, huh? - Am I?
无意冒犯 但你根本无法理解男女感情
No offense, but you're not capable of understanding the relationship.
好，不管怎么想 我们都逃不过的
Okay, any way you look at it, there is no light at the end of this tunnel.
无论如何，你和我都会死 你弟弟也是
One way or another, you and I, we die. Your brother too.
真可惜 在他为你做了这么多之后
Which is a shame, given all he's done for you.
我有个姐姐 我们十五年没说话了
I have a sister I haven't talked to in 15 years.
-你不觉得她这样过得比较好吗？ -我们会成功的
- You think she's better off for it? - We'll make it.
-刚刚那是信心吗？ -对，信心
- What is that, faith? - Yeah, that's faith.
我只看见一个黑洞
All I see is a black hole.
迟早，我们所有人 都会掉进去
And sooner or later, they're gonna suck each one of us into it.
但轮到我死时 我会杀一个算一个
But when they come for me, I'm gonna take as many of them with me as I can.
她一定伤你很深，保罗
She must have really broken your heart, Paul.
雷诺兹总统昨晚在芝加哥 参加一场慈善活动
President Reynolds attended a chicago fundraiser last night,,,
这是她在风城 两天访问行程的活动之一
,,, as part of her two-day stop in the Windy city,
雷诺兹在中西部的 支持率持续攀升
Reynolds' popularity continues to soar in the Midwest,,,
本周稍后她预计前往 印地安那波利
,,, with appearances scheduled in Indianapolis, Detroit,,,
密西根州的底特律 以及佛林特
,,, and Flint, Michigan later in the week,
密尔瓦基的 民主党筹款活动K
At a Democratic fundraiser in Milwaukee,,,,
金先生，莎拉丹奎迪 出现在芝加哥
Mr. Kim, sara Tancredi surfaced in Chicago.
她一小时前 出现在金皇冠俱乐部
She was spotted at the Corona de oro Club about an hour ago.
-金皇冠俱乐部？ -雪茄俱乐部，她父亲是会员
- Corona de oro Club? - It's a cigar club. Her father was a member.
他在里面有个恒温箱
He kept a private humidor there.
替我准备到芝加哥的飞机
Get me a jet to Chicago.
我得走了
航站在那里
我知道，我得去厕所
航站也有厕所
真的吗？谢谢你
谢谢你载我一程
你有备用枪吗？
你可能会需要，目标就是他
（追缉费南多苏克）
他已经来了
我刚刚才看到他
你不会还认为 他会出现吧？
Tell me you're not still thinking he's gonna show.
他让你失望太多次了 你很清楚
He's let you down so many times. You know that.
也许是肚里的宝宝告诉我 这一次他一定会来
Maybe it's the baby in me that's telling me that this time, it's gonna be different.
我不想戳破你的美梦 但他不会来的
I don't mean to burst your bubble, but he's not gonna show.
美梦没有破灭！
Bubble's not burst!
-我有三个字要说 -什么？
- I got three words for you. - Yeah?
我们跑
We gotta run.
回头见，泰瑞莎
We'll see you, Theresa.
（伊斯塔帕）
（计程车）
-很高兴你来了 -你真是个疯子
- I'm so glad you came. - You're crazy.
警察怎么知道？
How did they know?
你确定吗？
You're certain?
-确定箱子里的东西？ -不，但我们只有这条路可走
- About what's in the box? - No. But it's all we've got.
谢谢你，亨利
Thank you, Henry.
你确定要让他做？
You sure about this?
不确定
Nope.
不管怎样 你还欠我一顿晚餐
Either way, you still owe me dinner.
是吗？
Is that so?
对
Yep.
你到福克斯河第一个礼拜 答应我出去后要请我吃晚餐
First week in Fox River, you promised me if you got out, you'd take me to dinner.
也许办完这件事K
Well, maybe after we wrap this up, we can stop off...
回波普家的路上 我可以买牛肉卷请你吃
...and get you a burrito on the way back to Pope's house.
我不知道你的饮食习惯K
I don't know what you're used to...
可是没有菲力牛排 我是不会放过你的
...but anything short of a filet mignon is not gonna cut it with me.
就这么说定了
It's a date.
把手机给我
Give me the phone.
-喂 -你怎么说动他的？
- Hey. - How'd you pull it off?
-待会儿再说，他进去了吗？ -进去了
- I'll tell you later. Is he in yet? - Yep.
应该不用几分钟
This shouldn't take more than a couple minutes,
再久的话 我们就有麻烦了
Any longer than that, we'll know we've got trouble,
午安，波普先生 这边请
Good afternoon, Mr. Pope. Right this way.
谢谢
Thank you.
-波普先生 -华伦，你好吗？
- Mr. Pope. - Hey, Warren. How's it going?
你有听说今早的事吗？ 莎拉丹奎迪跑来了
You hear what happened this morning? Sara Tancredi came in.
有，我听说了
Yeah, so I heard.
下次K别再让她跑了
Well, next time, don't let her get away.
谢谢
Thanks.
（弗兰克丹奎迪）
不好意思 可以借用一下电脑吗？
Excuse me. You mind if I borrow your computer for a moment?
-没问题 -谢谢
- No problem. - Thanks.
来帮忙，孩子们
Pitch in, chitlins.
不行，我们不能住在这里
We can't do this. We can't live here.
这么乱当然不行 我们要整理，我们正在整理
Of course, not like this. We gonna clean. We are cleaning.
我们要重建这房子
We gonna rebuild.
你不能这样对他们 你自己看看他们
You can't do this to them. Look at them.
你们过来一下好吗？
You all mind coming along here for a minute?
过来，不用我再拿枪出来了吧
Come on. I think we're past me waving that gun around, don't you think?
进去，快点
In here. Now, come on.
-你要做什么？ -他们不会有事的，苏珊
- What are you doing? - Nothing is gonna happen to them, susan.
小苏珊，你以为 我带你们来这里K
Suzy Q., do you think I'd bring you here...
一个对我来说如此神圣的地方 难道会是要害你们吗？
...to so sacred a place to me as this, if I meant you ill?
看着我！
Look at me!
你眼前的人 不是你以为的禽兽
I am not the animal you think you see before you.
我是因果轮回下的受害者
I am the laws of karma all come down wrong.
-你还不懂吗？ -我不懂
- Don't you understand? - I don't.
我的意思是K
What I'm trying to say...
我是我父亲的罪恶
...is that I am the sin of my father.
-你说这些干嘛？ -因为我爱你
- Why are you telling me this? - Because I love you.
因为我要你了解我
Because I want you to understand me.
我是包威家族最后一人
I am the last in the line of Bagwells.
落血统的尾巴
The tail end of a corrupted breed.
感谢老天 地球上将不再有这家族的人
The earth, thank God, shall see no more of our generations.
我无法生育，苏珊
I cannot procreate, susan.
但这反而带给我极大的希望
And yet there's something in that that gives me great hope.
包威家族 不会再流窜在世上
No more Bagwells shall roam this planet.
这污秽的血统不再遗害人间
Not with that vile blood in their veins.
我只想终止这血统 连根铲除
All I wanna do is end that bloodline, extirpate it...
再重新来过
...and start another afresh.
-组成新的家庭 -泰迪
- A new family. - Oh, Teddy.
这两个孩子是我的救赎
Those children are my salvation.
让我把这世界 变得更美好的契机！
My chance to make this world a better place.
我会行善，苏珊
I will be good, susan.
我会爱他们 我会爱你
I will love them. I will love you.
我会信教、受洗 步上正道
I will take communion, be baptized under a truer light.
我只请求你回报我的爱 一点点就好
All I ask is that you love me back, just a little.
或者假以时日 学会爱上我也行
Or learn to do so in time.
你办得到吗，苏珊？
Can you do that, susan?
我办不到
I can't.
对不起
I'm sorry.
求求你K
Please. Please.
泰迪，求求你，天啊K
Teddy, please. Oh, God.
泰迪
Teddy.
泰迪，求求你
Teddy, please.
泰迪，对不起
Teddy, I'm sorry.
我办得到K
I can do it, I can do it...
（第八街诊所）
-这里是哪里？ -医生的诊所，甜心
- Where are we? - At the doctor's office, sweetie.
你好？有人吗？ 这里有紧急状况
Hello? Hello. I have an emergency in here.
有人吗？
Hello?
Hello.
-你是医生吗？ -你得排队
- Hey, you the doctor? - You need to wait your turn.
轮到我了 我有紧急状况
No, it is my turn. This is an emergency right here.
请你看看我女儿好吗？ 她不舒服
I need you to look at my daughter, okay? Now, she's not feeling too good.
拜托
Please.
甜心，等一下
Here, sweetie. Hold on.
对不起
I'm sorry.
拿去，我所有的钱都拿去
Hey, look, this is all the money I got, okay?
一共四百美金
That's $400.
请你看看我的女儿
Please look at my daughter.
-她怎么了？ -她有多囊性肾病
- What's the matter with her? - She has a kidney disease. PKD.
平常病情都受到控制 可是现在情况不妙
Normally, we have it under control, but I don't like what I'm seeing now.
她的肚子痛 而且体温一直很高
She's having stomach hurts, okay, she's always hot.
-进食状况呢？ -她毫无食欲
- How's her appetite? - It's gone.
-她一直很累，对吧宝贝？ -好吧
- She's always tired. Ain't that right, baby? - All right.
坐上来
Hop up here.
谢谢
Thank you.
医生会仔细帮你检查好吗？
Okay, he just wants to take a good look at you, okay?
-我可能要做一些检验 -尽量做没关系
- I may need to run a few tests. - Hey, just do what you have to do, man.
我就在旁边陪你，好吗？
I'm gonna be right here, okay, baby?
好
Okay.
-如何？ -情况如何？
- Yeah? - What's going on now?
他还在里面
He's still in there.
拖太久了
This is taking too long.
等等K他来了
Wait, wait, wait. Here he comes.
-怎么回事？ -有人来了
- What's happening? - We got company.
你好，亨利
Hello, Henry.
-我不知道你抽雪茄 -你是谁？
- Didn't know you were a cigar man. - Who are you?
一个朋友，应该说是同事 我们都是执法人员
A friend. A colleague, in fact. We're both in law enforcement.
我已经不是了
I'm not anymore.
也对，你退休了
That's right. You're retired.
-你认识他？ -对
- You know that guy? - Yeah.
看来你过得很悠闲 抽雪茄、喝美酒社交
Looks like the lifestyle's treating you well. Socializing over Cubans and cognac.
不过你不是来社交的吧？
But that's not what you were doing, is it?
亨利？
Henry?
不介意我请你掏空口袋吧？
You don't mind if I ask you to empty your pockets?
-事实上我介意 -我不打算玩游戏，亨利
- As a matter of fact, I do. - I'm not gonna play any games, Henry.
你今天来的原因 我们心知肚明
We both know why you came here today.
我建议你不要挡路，年轻人
I suggest you get out of my way, young man.
我办不到
I can't do that.
除非你想害自己 和家人惹上大麻烦
Unless you'd like to cause serious trouble for yourself and your family...
我建议你 把找到的东西交出来
...I advise you to hand over whatever it is you found.
立刻交出来
Now.
迈克K
Michael...
上车！
Get in!
走了！林克！
Let's go! Linc!
莎拉！
Sara!
不要怕K别紧张K
It's okay, it's okay. Easy, easy. It's okay, it's okay.
女士，你没事吧？
Ma'am, you all right?
怎么会这样？
I don't understand.
有人匿名通报说 这里有人被挟持
We got a call. Someone said there was a hostage situation here.
没有人知道我们在这里
No one knew we were here.
你没事吧？好
Are you okay? Okay.
情况如何？
So, what's going on?
令嫒恐怕有肾衰很的迹象
I'm afraid your daughter shows signs of renal failure.
她做过血液透析吗？
Has she ever had hemodialysis?
血液K没有K 以前没有这么严重过
No. Hemo...? No, no. This has never really gone that far.
你打算现在就做？
What, are you planning on doing it right here?
这里没办法做 她也还没准备好
We're not set up for it. Neither is she.
可是几条街外 有个郡立洗肾诊所
But there is a county dialysis clinic a few blocks away.
但我们得在她脖子上插导管 她才能接受检验
But we're going to have to place a catheter in her neck, so she can be examined.
不要动，甜心，会有点冷
Hold still, sweetie. This'll be a little cold.
没关系的，宝贝
It's okay, baby.
等等K那是什么？
Wait, wait, wait. What is that?
套针，用来插导管用的
It's a trocar. It's used for placing the catheter.
躺下，甜心
Lie down, honey.
-有必要做到这地步吗？ -听着K
- Do we really have to go this far? - Look...
我已经尽力在帮你 但你得认清一点
I'm doing the best I can here. But you gotta understand something.
你女儿生病了
Your daughter is sick.
这方法看似很极端 是因为情况紧急
Now, this may look like a desperate measure because it is.
会有点痛，甜心
This is gonna hurt a little bit, sweetie.
住手！住手
Stop! Stop.
走吧，宝贝
Come on, baby.
来吧，宝贝，我办不到
Come on, baby. I can't do this.
怎么回事？
What's going on?
我和波普谈好条件
I made a deal with Pope.
你和波普谈条件？ 什么条件？
You made a deal with Pope? What kind of deal?
如果他跟我们走 拿到我们要的东西K
If he came with us, and if we got what we needed...
我说我会自首
...I said I'd turn myself in.
什么？我们根本不知道 那是什么玩意儿
What? We don't even know what this thing is.
可能毫无用处，迈克 你知道这件事吗？
It could be nothing, Michael. You know about this?
他现在说了我才知道
Not until it came out of his mouth.
我只有这个办法
It was the only thing I could think of.
你们俩还是可以结束整件事 但我没办法帮忙了
You two can still finish this. You'll just have to do it without me.
我不会让你自首，迈克 这件事回不了头
I'm not gonna let you do this, Michael. There's no coming back from this.
-听着 -停下来干嘛？
- Now, look. - What's the holdup?
你哥说的对
Your brother's right.
法院绝不会对你宽容以待
I wouldn't count on the courts to show you any leniency in this.
没关系，我说过 我会遵守诺言
That doesn't matter. I said I'd hold up my end of the deal.
你已经遵守了
You already did.
我听过内容，这证据很重要
I listened to this. You have something here.
很多人会因此遭殃 但现在已经在你手上
There are gonna be a lot of people who wish you didn't, but you do.
-亨利K -我若是你，就会马上走
- Listen, Henry... - I'd go now, if I were you.
别以为我原谅你了
And don't consider this forgiveness.
事实上，我可能 马上会改变心意
In fact, I'm about 10 seconds away from changing my mind.
谢谢你
Thank you.
好K
Okay.
来吧K
Here, let's...
把帽子戴上，好吗？
Let's tuck you in, all right? Okay?
来，我们走
Come on, let's go.
听着，我们再坐着 休息一下
Listen, let's just sit for a little bit longer, okay?
等一下再走，好吗？
We're gonna go in a little bit, okay?
你知道爸爸很爱你，对吧？
You know Daddy loves you with all his heart, right?
我好爱你
I love you so much.
我真的对不起你
I'm so sorry.
对不起，宝贝
I'm so sorry, baby.
-什么事？ -有你的电话
- Yeah? - I got a call for you.
我再回电 刚接到北边的诊所通报
I'll call back. I just heard from some clinic up north.
富兰克林半小时前去过那里
They had contact with Franklin half an hour ago.
你最好接这通电话
I think you want to take this.
接过来
Put it through.
我是曼宏
Yeah? Mahone.
-你是负责人吗？ -对
- Is this the man in charge? - Oh, yeah,
我是班哲明迈尔斯富兰克林
My name is Benjamin Miles Franklin.
（电话）
我要自首
And I wanna turn myself in.
但我有一个条件
But I got one condition,
把我妻子放出来
My wife, well, she goes free,
我女儿需要母亲
My little daughter, she needs her mother.
我没必要跟你谈条件 富兰克林先生
I don't think I need to make a deal with you, Mr. Franklin.
如果我有你要的资讯呢？
What if I got something you need?
（赶快康复）
你的妻子一小时前已经出狱 她马上会过来
Your wife was released an hour ago. She'll be here soon.
答应我她会好起来
Promise me that she will be okay.
只要你遵守诺言
Just hold up your end of the deal.
我会的
I will.
我会帮你抓到斯科菲尔德
I'll get you scofield.
拿去
Here we go.
你觉得会是对话内容吗？
You think it's a conversation?
是不可告人的对话
One they don't want us to hear.
-准备好了吗？ -放吧
- You ready? - Let's do it.